[Road to Success]
[星のように煌めく]
[Episode 26]
[第26話]
-Come on, eat up. -It's ready.
- 早く食べろ - もう食べれるぞ
-Slow down. -Guys,
- ゆっくり - お前たち
Lin Lu and Zheng Feiyang's barbecue is here!
林鹿と鄭飛揚が焼いた バーベキューだぞ
-Finally! -Smells so good!
- やっと来たか - すごくいい匂い！
-Finally done. -How do we roast the corn?
- ついに来た - このトウモロコシは どうやって焼んだ？
There's no occasion
どんなお祝い事も
a hot pot can't celebrate.
火鍋で解決できないことはない
If there is, throw a barbecue too.
もしダメなら バーベキューを追加すればいい
And if the occasion's big enough,
祝うことがそれだけ大事なら
have both.
一つにまとめればいいだろ
So,
では
to celebrate our team, Hongjing No. 8 High,
我々 宏景第八高校が
beating 2 professional league youth teams
プロリーグ傘下の２チームを抑え
and advancing from
総勝ち点６
the group stage in second place with 6 points,
グループ２位で 勝ち抜けたことを祝して
let's raise a glass!
みんなで乾杯しよう
Come on, come on!
ほら ほら
-Cheers! -Come on, cheers!
- 乾杯！ - 乾杯しよう！
Thank you, Coach!
ありがとう コーチ
Thank you, Coach.
コーチ ありがとう
-Thank you, Coach.
- ありがとう コーチ
Eat up.
食え
I'm going to grab some barbecue.
バーベキュー取ってくる
-Throw in some meatballs -Feng Suo.
- ミートボールを入れろ - 馮鎖
No need.
いや いい
The corn is on the grill.
トウモロコシを焼いた
Want some corn?
トウモロコシ食べる？
Chengye,
文くん
how have you been lately?
最近 どう？
Give me a chicken wing.
手羽先をくれ
As long as there are matches to play, I'm good.
サッカーができるだけで十分です
Cut it out, you guys!
騒ぐなよ
One skewer each!
1人1本だ
How are things at home?
ご家族は元気？
Fine, fine.
はいはい
One at a time.
順番に来い
Ever since we started winning,
最近 試合に勝ってから
they've stopped complaining.
家では何も言われなくなりました
Thank you.
どうも
Actually, I've always felt
私 思うんだけど
you shouldn't be trapped by your past.
過去に囚われるべきじゃないわ
Your parents,
ご両親や
your family,
家庭
and everything you've been through—
あなたが将来どんな人になるかを
none of that should
これまでの経験すべてで
define who you'll become.
決めるものじゃない
Then...
じゃあ
then what does define it?
なら何が決めるんですか
Yourself, of course.
もちろん自分自身よ
Only you
あなただけが
can define who you are.
自分を定義できるの
Wen Chengye,
文成業
it's a disgrace not to help out, you know.
働かざる者食うべからずだぞ
Qin Ao, did you help?
秦敖 お前こそ働いたか
Nope.
いや 働いてない
So I'm a disgrace.
だから恥ずかしいんだよ
You're so shameless.
恥知らずめ
Who are you calling shameless?
誰が恥知らずだと？
Ms. Lin, you've made huge strides
林先生は最近 教育者として
in education lately.
目覚ましいな
It's alright.
そうでもないわ
But tonight, the spotlight definitely belongs to you, Coach Wang.
今日の主役は王大コーチでしょ
Come on, let's drink till we drop.
さあ 飲むわよ
No oysters?
牡蠣は注文しなかった
Why are you taking so much?
そんなにたくさん載せてどうする？
I'm just grabbing some meat.
肉を少し取りたいだけだ
I'm not eating that much.
そんなにたくさん食べられるのか
Give him the food.
彼に渡せ
Ms. Lin,
林先生
look at Wen Chengye making a fool of himself.
文成業のバカっぷりを見て
You're a bigger fool than I am.
お前のほうがバカだ
Am I walking okay?
私の歩き方どう？
You're walking perfectly fine.
林先生はちゃんと歩いてるぞ
We're here.
着いた
Hold on.
待って
I dribble...
突破
Shoot!
シュート
You scored?
ゴールだな
Don't I have talent for football?
私ってサッカーの才能 あると思わない？
You do.
あるさ
My feet are so cold.
足が冷たい
What? Not feeling well?
どうした？気分でも悪いのか？
I'll go get some water for you.
水を持ってくる
Wang Fa...
王法
Wang Fa, where are you going?
王法 どこ行くの？
I'm glad you're here, Wang Fa.
王法がいてくれて本当によかった
Alright.
よし
Rest early.
早く休んで
♪ I caught your eyes ♪
♪ 君のまなざしを見つけた ♪
♪ On the summer night ♪
♪ あの夏の夜に ♪
♪ Like stars that glow so bright ♪
♪ 眩しく輝く星のようだった ♪
Do... Do I have a talent for football?
私 サッカーの才能あるかな？
You do.
ある
♪ A spark in my heart ♪
♪ 胸に灯る小さな火は ♪
♪ Lost in a dream secretly ♪
♪ 夢の中へ そっと消えてゆく ♪
♪ With the evening breeze whispering in my ear ♪
♪ 夜風が耳元に 吹き寄せる告白 ♪
Shoot!
シュート
I scored... Another goal...
ゴール また決めた
♪ Fireworks bloom across the sky ♪
♪ 空いっぱいの花火が 咲き誇る ♪
Attack!
攻めて
One more!
もう１発
♪ Shimmering in your eyes ♪
♪ あなたの瞳に映り込んで ♪
Shoot!
シュート
Take another shot!
もう１発
♪ And spreading into a gentle sea of stars ♪
♪ やさしさとなって広がる 星の海 ♪
What's the score now?
今 何対何？
Ten to zero.
10対０だ
♪ Every night ♪
♪ 毎晩 ♪
Who's got 10?
10は誰で ０は誰？
♪ I reach for starlight ♪
♪ 星の光に 手を伸ばす ♪
You do. I've got 0.
君は10 私は０
♪ Wandering through dreams with you ♪
♪ 君と夢の中を彷徨う ♪
Go to sleep.
寝て
♪ I follow the beat of my heart ♪
♪ 鼓動のリズムに乗せて ♪
♪ Like dust floating in the air ♪
♪ 宙を舞う塵のように ♪
♪ Because of your love ♪
♪ 君の愛が ♪
♪ I shine brilliantly ♪
♪ 私を輝かせる ♪
♪ I caught your eyes ♪
♪ 君のまなざしを見つけた ♪
♪ On the summer night ♪
♪ あの夏の夜に ♪
♪ Like stars that glow so bright ♪
♪ 眩しく輝く星のようだった ♪
♪ A spark in my heart ♪
♪ 胸に灯る小さな火は ♪
♪ Lost in a dream secretly ♪
♪ 夢の中へ そっと消えてゆく ♪
Why is my room so clean?
何でこんなにきれいなの？
Did you turn into a little house elf, Coach?
コーチが 片付け妖精さんになったのね
[Winfred]
[ウィンフレッド]
You're up.
起きたか
Where's my facial cleansing brush?
洗顔ブラシは？
[Winfred]
[ウィンフレッド]
What brush?
洗顔ブラシ？
The one I left on the bathroom sink.
洗面台に置いてたやつ
I know which one.
ああ あれか
But are you sure you still want it?
でもまだ欲しいのか
Looking for your facial cleansing brush?
洗顔ブラシを探そうか？
Why is it here?
なんでここにあるの？
This isn't meant for cleaning shoes, right?
これって靴用ブラシじゃないよな？
What would a clueless guy like you know?
女心の分からない男に 何が分かるわけ？
It's whatever kind of brush I say it is.
これが何のブラシかは私が決めるの
Why didn't you stop me?
どうして止めなかったの？
You insisted on cleaning your shoes yourself.
林先生がどうしても 自分でやるから
I couldn't stop you.
私には止められなかった
I'll have to buy another one.
また買わなきゃ
Don't worry.
安心しろ
I've ordered the latest model for you.
最新モデルを注文しといたから
Make sure you get it when it arrives.
受け取って
Really?
本当？
That's so sweet.
気が利くじゃない
I'm hungry.
お腹すいた
Let's go to your place for a healthy meal.
あなたの家で ヘルシーなご飯を食べに行く
We'll eat at your place today.
今日は君の家で
I'll cook for you.
私が作る
You know how to cook?
料理もできるの？
You're making fried noodles for me?
まさかこれが私に作ってるご飯？
Let me show you the superb cooking skills
イギリス留学帰りの
of a UK returnee.
腕前を見せてやる
Then I'm looking forward to it.
じゃあお手並み拝見ね
I'm going to wash up.
顔を洗ってくる
It looks quite good.
見た目はなかなかいいじゃない
Go on, try it.
早く食べてみろ
It tastes even better than it looks.
見た目以上においしい
Really? Then have some more.
そうか じゃあ たくさん食べろ
I'm full and happy.
大満足
Since Coach House-Elf
妖精コーチが
showed off his amazing cooking,
見事な腕前を披露してくれたから
I must return the favor.
私もお返しをしないと
Close your eyes.
目を閉じて
From now on, if you want to come over,
今度から家に入る時は
you don't need to knock.
ノックしなくていいから
Just use the key.
鍵で入ってきて
You always hide the key
林先生はいつも鍵を
under the shoe cabinet.
靴箱の下に隠してる
I can get in without knocking anyway.
ノックしなくても入れる
You knew that?
それも知ってたの？
Thank you, Ms. Lin, for formally accepting me.
林先生 正式な認可をありがとう
Parachute drop, follow me.
パラシュートでついてきて
[Fishing Village]
[漁村]
Stick with me.
私をフォローして
Enemy, southwest, 450 degrees!
南西450度に敵
There are too many of them. I'm hiding.
人が多すぎるから隠れる
-I… -Shoot, shoot!
- 私... - 打って 打って 打って
It's all on you now.
もうあなたに頼るしかない
Leave it to me...
私に頼る？
Gotta say, that meal of yours
さっきのお昼ご飯で
really worked up my appetite.
すごく食欲をそそられた
For dinner...
夜ご飯は
For dinner, let's have some pan-fried buns from Granny Wu's.
呉おばあさんの 焼き小籠包にしよう？
It's only 4:30 PM now.
まだ４時半だぞ
People start lining up there by 5 PM.
あそこは５時には行列ができるの
I'm dead too.
私もやられた
[Ms. Lin Wanxing, please come to the school immediately.]
林晚星先生 すぐに学校に来て 私を訪ねてください
The principal wants to see me.
校長先生が私を？
It's the weekend. What could he want?
週末なのに 何の用かしら？
Go ahead.
行っておいで
Don't worry about the pan-fried buns.
焼き小籠包は任せて
I'll go line up for you.
代わりに並んでおくから
I'll leave it to you then.
お願いね
[Superstar Slacker]
[干物見習い]
Ms. Lin's gone hunting.
林先生は狩りに出かける
Wait for me to come back.
戻ってきたら
We'll eat the pan-fried buns together.
焼き小籠包を食べようね
Bye.
じゃあね
[Administrative Building]
[管理棟]
Come in.
どうぞ
Principal, you wanted to see me?
校長先生 お呼びでしょうか
Ms. Lin.
ああ 林先生
Sit.
まあ
I asked you here today
今日来てもらったのは
because there's something
少し あなたと
I need to verify with you.
確認したいことがあってね
Ms. Lin.
林先生
Your boyfriend's been waiting for you there for quite a while.
彼氏がずいぶん待っているようです
Have you been waiting long?
そんなに待ってたの？
I bought you the pan-fried buns.
焼き小籠包 買ってきたぞ
Why did it take so long?
ずいぶん長かったな
They're cold now.
冷めちゃったぞ
You actually got them.
本当に買えたのね？
Let's go.
行こっか
Did the principal ask you anything?
校長先生に何か聞かれたか
He just asked a few things about the team's
チームの今後の
next stage now that we've advanced.
昇格について聞かれただけ
He's that eager?
せっかちだな
Calling you in on a weekend just for that.
日曜にわざわざ 呼び出して聞くなんて
Building a stronger sporting nation.
スポーツ大国だから
What's wrong with caring about the next generation?
未来の世代を思うのはいいことよ
What's the filling in these?
この小籠包は何味なの？
They're cold now.
もう冷めてる
Don't eat them yet.
すぐには食べられない
Let's heat them up when we get back.
帰って温め直そう
Okay.
うん
I've got a bit of a headache.
ちょっと頭が痛いから
I want to rest first.
先に休むね
Why the sudden headache?
急にどうしたんだ？
Maybe I didn't sleep well last night.
昨日の夜 よく眠れなかったのかも
But you haven't eaten yet.
でも まだ何も食べてないだろ
Aren't there pan-fried buns?
焼き小籠包があるじゃない
Remember to heat them up in the oven.
オーブンで温めろよ
Lin Wanxing.
林晚星
Are you really okay?
本当に大丈夫か
I'm fine.
大丈夫
I'm just a little tired.
ちょっと疲れてるだけ
Don't worry, Coach House-Elf.
安心して 妖精コーチ
See you tomorrow.
また明日ね
Someone has reported
君が永川大学で
[Report Letter]
[密告書]
that you were expelled
不名誉な理由で退学になったと
from Yongchuan University for some unsavory reasons.
密告があってね
Ms. Lin,
林先生
the school trusts you deeply.
学校は君を信頼しているんだ
We hope you'll handle this matter properly.
うまく対処してくれ
[Over a year ago]
[１年以上前]
Professor Shu?
舒教授
Save him!
助けろ
-Professor Shu!
- 舒教授
Call an ambulance!
電話をしろ
Hello?
もしもし
[Goodbye, My Love]
[さらば 愛する人へ]
Is that Lin Wanxing?
あれって林晚星じゃない？
The one who seduced a professor and knowingly became the other woman?
教授を誘惑して 不倫相手になったっていう子?
Yeah.
そうよ
Professor Shu was a good man.
舒教授はいい人よ
I even took his class.
私も彼の授業に行ったことあるわ
[Withdrawal Application]
[退学申請届]
If you apply to withdraw from school now,
今すぐ退学すれば
you can still preserve what little dignity is left
あなたと舒教授の
for yourself and Professor Shu.
名誉だけは守れるわ
Mom,
母さん
even you don't believe me?
あなたまで私を信じてくれないの？
Sign it.
それに署名しなさい
Grandpa...
おじいちゃんが
passed away.
亡くなったの
That's impossible.
ありえない
Where is Grandpa?
おじいちゃんはどこ？
I want to see him!
会いに行く
He's already been cremated.
もう火葬したわ
What?
何だって？
Why didn't you tell me?
どうして教えてくれなかったの？
Where are you going?
どこ行くんだ？
Wanxing, isn't it inappropriate for you to be here?
晚星 ここにいては まずいんじゃない？
Shuyun,
淑雲
what do you mean by that?
どういうつもりで言ってるの？
Aunt,
叔母
you and Uncle devoted your whole lives to teaching
叔母と叔父は生涯 教育に身を捧げ
and earned everyone's respect.
ずっと尊敬されてきたのに
But Wanxing is a disappointment
この晚星が期待を裏切って
and has let you down.
ご恩をあだで返したのよ
If you ask me, she never should've come back.
私に言わせれば 帰ってくるべきじゃなかった
Alright, you've offered the incense.
もういいでしょう お焼香は済んだのだから
You can leave now.
お引き取りを
Aunt, I'm only thinking of you.
叔母 私はお二人のために 言ってるんです
When Uncle was gravely ill,
叔父が重病の時に
she was out there doing those shameful things,
あの子は外で恥さらしなことをして
making you both suffer!
あなた方を苦しめた
If it hadn't been for her,
あの子のせいで
Uncle wouldn't have passed away!
叔父が亡くなったのよ
Aunt Shuyun.
おばさん
Those were just rumors.
それは全部デマです
Rumors?
デマだって？
There's no smoke without fire.
火のない所に煙は立たないわ
Why pick on you and not the others?
なんで他の人じゃなく あなたが言われるの？
I believe Wanxing!
私はこの子を信じる
I won't let you insult her!
この子を侮辱するのは許さない
I insult her?
私が侮辱したと？
She still hasn't reflected on herself to this day.
この子は今も反省してない
Do you know what everyone's been
親戚中で
saying about her in the family?
どう言われてるか知ってるの？
She's just brought shame to you!
あなた方の顔に泥を塗り
-To our whole family! -Enough!
- 私たち家族全員に恥をかかせたのよ - もういい
Shut up!
黙りなさい
Me? Shut up?
私が黙る？
Aunt, you threw my kindness back in my face!
叔母 人の好意を無にするなんて
-You really... -Get out!
本当に
You can get out now!
今すぐ出ていって
-Me? -She's the one who should get out!
出ていくべきなのはこの子よ
-Grandma! Grandma! -Grandma!
- おばあちゃん
Grandma,
おばあちゃん
it's all my fault.
全部 私のせい
If it hadn't been for me,
私のせいでなければ
you wouldn't have been like this.
こんなことにはならなかった
[Superstar Slacker]
[干物見習い]
How are you? Does your head still hurt?
具合はどう？まだ頭は痛い？
I'm okay. I took some medicine, and I'm going to sleep.
うん 頭痛薬を飲んだ 寝るね
[Superstar Slacker]
[干物見習い]
Good night. See you tomorrow.
おやすみ また明日
Lin Wanxing, it's 7:30.
林晚星 ７時半だ
Time to get up.
起きる時間だぞ
I bought you rice noodle rolls.
腸粉を買ってきたぞ
Wanxing?
晚星
We're going to be late...
遅刻するぞ
Lin Wanxing!
林晚星
[I'm sorry. I've already left.]
[ごめん もう離れたの]
I'm sorry. I've already left.
ごめん もう離れたの
Wanxing!
星星
Lin Wanxing!
林晚星
Where is Wanxing?
星星は？
Her phone's off.
電源が入ってない
She sent me this WeChat message early this morning.
このメッセージ 朝早くに送られてきたの
I called her right after seeing it,
気づいて すぐに電話したんだけど
but I couldn't get through.
ずっとつながらない
[Li, I've left. I'll leave the team to you.]
[礼ちゃん 私はもう離れる チームのことは任せるね]
[All the materials are on my coffee table.]
[資料は全部テーブルの上よ]
Did something happen to her?
あの子に何かあったの？
The principal spoke with her for a long time yesterday.
昨日 学長と長く話していた
She wasn't herself after she came back.
帰ってきてから 様子がおかしかったんだ
In the end...
ついに
it happened after all.
すべて起きてしまった
No,
だめ
I have to go find her.
探しに行かなきゃ
Are you just going to run around looking for her like a headless chicken?
やみくもに探す気か
Tell me first,
何があったのか
what happened?
まず教えてくれ
I had no idea
まさか
she'd been through all that.
そんなつらい経験をしていたなんて
I don't believe those rumors.
私はうわさなんて信じない
But what difference does it make?
でも私１人が 信じなくても意味ないの
Plenty of people do.
信じる人は大勢いるから
After Wanxing dropped out of Yongchuan,
星星は永川を退学してから
she went through a really difficult time.
つらい日々を送ってた
Actually, ever since she was little,
あの子は小さい頃から
she's always been a very, very strong girl.
すごく芯の強い子だったの
I remember...
覚えてる
back in middle school,
中学の時
a chubby kid in our class falsely accused her of stealing his pen.
クラスの太った子が万年筆を 盗んだって濡れ衣を着せたの
She chased after him and beat him up.
そしたらその子を追いかけて
She even grabbed his backpack
かばんを奪い取って
until she found
その万年筆を
the pen inside.
見つけ出すまでやめなかった
I still remember
その時
her holding up that pen
あの子が万年筆を持って
and splattering ink all over him. She looked so cool.
インクをそいつに ぶちまけたのかっこよかった
But not every situation gives a person...
だけど いつでも
the chance to prove their innocence.
潔白を証明できるわけじゃない
You came back to Hongjing after learning about
君もその件を知って
all that, didn't you?
宏景に戻ってきたんだろ？
After we went our separate ways,
昔 彼女と離れてから
I always kept a close eye on her.
ずっとＳＮＳを 特別フォローしてたの
I often checked her various social media accounts.
いつも彼女の投稿をチェックしてた
At some point, I noticed she'd suddenly disappeared.
ある時 ぱったりと 更新が途絶えたの
So I called people at Yongchuan
だから永川の人に電話して
to ask about her.
彼女の状況を聞いてみた
That was when I found out
その時初めて
she'd gotten into trouble.
何か起きたと知った
In front of her, I always pretended
彼女の前ではずっと
I didn't know anything.
何も知らないふりをしてた
I thought...
戻ればそばにいてあげられる
I could be there for her if I came back.
もし耐えられなくなったら
If she really couldn't get through it,
一緒にスイスに帰ろうって
I'd take her back to Switzerland with me.
思ったの
I thought she'd finally healed...
今はやっと元気になったと
and that she'd found the right man too.
それにいい人にも 巡り会えたと思ってたのに
I failed to protect her.
私が守れなかった
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team Training Unit Plan]
[宏景第八高校訓練計画表]
That's all I know.
私が知ってるのはこれだけ
No matter what, I still have to go find her.
どっちにしろ探しに行く
Even if I can't find her...
見つからなくても
I'll do my best to hold the fort for her.
彼女の代わりに しっかりチームを守るわ
Li,
礼ちゃん
I've left.
私はもう離れる
I'll leave the team to you.
チームのことは任せるね
All the materials are on my coffee table.
資料は全部テーブルの上よ
He's a light sleeper,
彼は眠りが浅いから
so I can't send him a WeChat message.
メッセージは送らない
I'm sorry.
ごめん
I've already left.
もう離れたの
[I'm sorry. I've already left.]
[ごめん もう離れたの]
[Knowledge is Boundless]
[学に終わりなし]
"Xiju." (Comedy)
コメディ
Comedy.
ｃｏｍｅｄｙ
How to spell it?
どうスペルするんだ？
Okay.
よし
"Kouyin." (Accent)
アクセント
Accent.
ａｃｃｅｎｔ
Okay, how to spell it?
よし スペルは？
Hey, check the forum.
掲示板を見ろ
It's Ms. Lin from the sports equipment room, right?
体育用具室の林先生じゃない？
Her dirty past has been exposed!
黒歴史が暴露された
[Lin Wanxing, Sports Equipment Room Teacher: Morally Corrupt,]
[体育用具室の教師 林晚星の道徳的堕落]
Knowingly the other woman, and responsible for a professor's death?
不倫と知ってて 教授を死なせたって
[Knowingly the Other Woman, Responsible for a Professor's Death,]
[不倫相手と知りながら関係を持ち 教授を死なせる]
-What? -What the hell is this?
- いや - これは一体何だ？
[Lin Wanxing, Sports Equipment Room Teacher: Morally Corrupt,]
[体育用具室の教師 林晚星の道徳的堕落]
Turn it off! Turn it off!
消せ 消せ
[Knowingly the Other Woman, Responsible for a Professor's Death,]
[不倫相手と知りながら関係を持ち 教授を死なせる 永川大学から除名]
Let's go find Ms. Lin.
林先生を探しに行くぞ
Let's go. Come on.
行くぞ
Is it real?
マジかよ
Turn that off!
消さないと
I didn't see her.
見えない
Is she over here?
こっちは？
Not in here.
ここにはいない
Not over here either.
こっちもだ
[Sports Equipment Room]
[体育用具保管室]
Is Ms. Lin not here?
林先生はいないのか？
You saw the forum too, right?
掲示板を見たのか
I'm not sure whether Ms. Lin has seen it yet.
林先生が見たかどうかは分からない
Let's hope she hasn't.
見てないといいけど
How could she not?
見てないわけないだろ
I don't know where she went.
今 どこに行ったか分からないんだ
Text Ms. Lin on your phone.
スマホで林先生にメッセージしろ
Let's just go find her directly.
いっそ直接探しに行こう
Do you know where she is?
どこにいるか知ってるのか
Everyone, let's go back to class first.
みんな いったん戻れ
We'll figure something out together after school.
放課後にまた考えよう
Let's go.
行くぞ
[Good thing I'm not on the football team. I don't have to face this.]
[サッカーチームに所属していなくてよかった そんな問題に巻き込まれないで済む ]
[She's quite a piece of work. So who's she after]
[彼女 そんなに凄いんなら 私たちの学校に来たのは 誰に手出ししたいわけ？]
[at our school? Old Demon Jin and Qian don't have anything worth taking, anyway.]
[チビ金と老謙だとしても 何も得をしないだろ？]
[Disgusting. Apparently, anyone can be a teacher now.]
[気持ち悪い 誰でも教師になれるのね]
[If this gets out,]
[これ校外に流れたら]
[we'll never be able to hold our heads up when dealing with other schools.]
[もう他の学校の前で 胸を張って歩けない]
[Let's all sign a petition to drive Lin Wanxing out.]
[力を合わせて 林晚星を追い出そう]
[The problem now is not who hired her.]
[今問題なのは 誰が彼女を 八高に入れさせたのじゃなくて]
[The real question is what the school will do with her—fire her or keep her?]
[どう対処するか 解雇すべきか 職にとどまらせるべきかだ]
[The thread title sounds kind of personal.]
[この肩書きには 個人感情が込められている]
[Maybe the OP got rejected by her.]
[投稿者は愛が 憎しみに変わったのか？]
[Otherwise, why be so obsessed with a teacher from the equipment room?]
[そうでないと なぜ管理人ごときに それほど気を配るの？]
When I was 8 years old,
私が８歳の時
my dad also wronged me once.
父にぬれぎぬを着せられたの
The things he said to scold me
その時 父に罵られた言葉が
haunted me
私の心の中の
for quite a while.
消えないトラウマになった
So much so that even after I grew up,
それで大人になっても
whenever I hit a setback,
壁にぶつかると
thinking of what he'd said back then
当時の父の言葉を思い出して
would shatter my courage to face difficulties.
困難に立ち向かう勇気を 失ってしまうの
It wasn't me.
私じゃない
I didn't do those things.
何もしてない
I didn't do it.
私じゃないの
A few months ago,
数か月前
I was in a really bad state.
私の精神状態は本当にひどかった
I also stood at the edge of a very high place.
私も高い所に立って
[Let's end it then. I don't want to see you again.]
[もう終わりにする さようなら]
[Start from the highest point.]
[最高地点からスタート]
I thought...
心の中で思ったの
[At least I can hold onto the feeling of flying for a few seconds.]
[少なくとも数秒間は 飛んでいる感覚を味わえる]
if I just jumped,
飛び降りさえすれば
I'd finally be free.
楽になれるんじゃないかと
So
そうか
this is what she'd been through—
彼女はこんな ひどい目に遭っていたのか
slandered, expelled,
中傷され 退学させられ
and locked up by her parents.
親に閉じ込められ
She couldn't even see her beloved grandfather
大好きな祖父の死に目にも
for the last time.
会えなかった
Yet she still put up a strong front
それでも気丈に振る舞い
and chose to stay.
ここに とどまることを選んだ
But Wang Fa, what did you do?
それなのに王法 お前は
You doubted her
彼女を疑い
and investigated her.
探り
You tore open her deepest wound—
誰にも信じてもらえないという
the wound of not being trusted.
彼女の深い傷をえぐったんだ
Wang Fa,
王法
how could you possibly deserve her forgiveness?
お前に彼女から 許される資格があるか
Lin Wanxing,
林晚星
no matter where you've gone,
君がどこへ行こうと
I will find you,
必ず見つけ出して
and I'll be there to catch you.
受け止める
Fu, are you stupid or what?
付 バカか
That bastard was badmouthing Ms. Lin,
あの林先生の悪口を 言っている野郎と
and you went after him all by yourself?
一人でケンカを売るなんて
Did you have no one backing you up?
仲間がいないとでも
Or did we all die or something?
思ったか
Yeah! Next time something like this happens, tell us.
そうだ 今後は俺たちに言え
You have to tell us when something happens.
何かあったら相談しろ
Okay, I know.
はい 分かった
Do you think Ms. Lin will come back today?
林先生は今日 戻ってくるかな？
How would I know?
さあな
Hard to say.
どうだか
I don't know.
わかんない
Hello, Ms. Ju.
先生 こんにちは
Everyone,
みんな
starting today,
今日から私が
I'm your new team supervisor.
あなたたちの新しい顧問よ
Wait, how did you become our supervisor?
はあ なんであなたが顧問なんだ？
Our supervisor is Ms. Lin.
俺たちの顧問は林先生だ
Yeah, it can only be Ms. Lin.
そうだ 林先生しかいない
Ms. Lin...
林先生は
has to step away for a while.
しばらくチームを離れる
Without Ms. Lin,
林先生がいないなら
what's the point of playing football?
サッカーなんてやってられるか
Yeah, without Ms. Lin,
そうだ 林先生がいなきゃ
this team would have been disbanded long ago.
サッカー部なんてとっくにない
The team's heart isn't here. What are we even playing for?
チーム魂が来なきゃ やる気も出ない
Do you all trust Ms. Lin?
みんなは林先生を信じるか
Of course.
当然だ
That doesn't even need asking!
当たり前だろ
Then, do you still remember
林先生に出した宿題の答えを
the answer you handed in for Ms. Lin's assignment?
覚えているか
[We]
[サ]
[We play football to win]
[サッカーは勝利を目指すもの]
This is the answer you gave her.
これが君たちの答えだ
But if you give up football now,
だが今サッカーを諦めたら
then when I bring Ms. Lin back,
私が林先生を連れ戻した時
will you still be able to tell her
サッカーは勝利のためだと
that you play football to win?
先生に胸を張って言えるのか
Coach,
コーチ
can you really bring Ms. Lin back?
本当に先生を連れ戻せるのか
I can.
ああ
But will you be able to
だが君たちは
welcome her back with a victory?
林先生を勝利で 迎える準備ができているか
[We play football to win]
[サッカーは勝利を目指すもの]
Okay.
よし
I've reviewed the materials.
資料は見たわ
Our next match is in 2 weeks.
次の試合は２週間後よ
Wang Fa, I'm still looking for her.
王法 まだ捜索中よ
[Wang Tian]
[王天]
Wait for my news.
連絡を待って
You're really something.
たいしたもんだわ
You came all the way here, but you wouldn't come up to my office.
来たならオフィスに寄りなさいよ
And I had to come down to see you personally.
私を呼び出すなんて
Tian, did you find anything?
姉さん 手がかりは？
Seeing you like this,
その様子じゃ
I don't even feel like teasing you.
冗談を言う気にもなれないわ
She was spotted in Hanling,
彼女は韓嶺に現れた事があったわ
but I didn't track down her exact location.
でも詳しい場所までは分からない
Hanling...
韓嶺
Sitting around at a dog café waiting like this
犬カフェで待ち伏せなんて
is really dumb, you know.
本当にバカみたいだ
Hanling is huge.
韓嶺は広いし
There are tons of dog cafés.
犬カフェもたくさんある
Then I'll search them one by one.
じゃあ一軒一軒探す
You'd be better off letting me hire a private investigator.
だったら私立探偵に 頼んだほうがマシ
No.
ダメだ
She probably just wants to be alone right now.
彼女は今 １人になりたいはずだ
Then why are you here?
じゃあ なぜここに来た？
She can choose not to see me...
彼女が会いたくなくても
but I have to be there for her.
私はそばにいなきゃいけない
I get it.
分かった
You're doing that whole "moved by your own devotion" thing.
自己満足に浸りたいわけだ
I'm right here with you, bro.
付き合うよ
Take that off.
外せ
They don't want to wear it,
この子たちも嫌がるから
so someone has to.
誰かがつけないと
You're back.
お帰り
Let me put it on you.
ほら つけるぞ
♪ Our words flow ♪
♪ 言葉はそっと ♪
No. One more. Is that enough?
もう一つどう？足りた？
♪ A gentle stream ♪
♪ 優しい川のように流れて ♪
Yeah, that's enough.
もう十分だ
♪ They glow like fireflies ♪
♪ 蛍のあかりが ♪
♪ Inside a silken dream ♪
♪ 柔らかな夢へと舞い降りる ♪
♪ We talk the cool night, breeze away ♪
♪ 夜通し語れば 夜風も静かに眠ってゆく ♪
♪ We trace the roads ♪
♪ この長い道を ♪
♪ That never see an end ♪
♪ どこまでも歩いていこう ♪
♪ We softly calm the hidden doubt ♪
♪ そっと拭ってあげる ♪
Our quarterfinal opponent this time will be
準々決勝の相手は
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League] [Quarterfinals]
[永川省ユーススーパーリーグ 準々決勝]
♪ Seen in each other's eyes ♪
♪ その瞳に浮かぶ迷いを ♪
Hanling Victory.
韓嶺勝利よ
Coach Wang Fa prepared these for you.
これは王法コーチがみんなに 用意してくれた資料よ
Pass them around.
回して見て
♪ And wake the warmth inside ♪
♪ 胸の奥で秘められた 温もりを呼び覚ます ♪
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League] [Quarterfinals]
[永川省ユーススーパーリーグ 準々決勝]
♪ Life begins alone ♪
♪ 人生は一人で歩き始め ♪
♪ A road we walk alone ♪
♪ 孤独な道を進んでゆく ♪
♪ Until fate brings warmth ♪
♪ だけど運命が温もりを運び ♪
♪ To light our way back home ♪
♪ 帰る場所を照らしてくれた ♪
♪ True love is not just ♪
♪ 愛とはただ ♪
♪ The gaze when two hearts first meet ♪
♪ 初めて出会った 一瞬のまなざしじゃなく ♪
♪ It's courage in the arms ♪
♪ 抱きしめ合うときの 揺るがぬ勇気 ♪
♪ We stand as one ♪
♪ 心を一つに寄り添って ♪
[Hongjing No. 8 High 2–0 Hanling Victory]
[宏景八高 02] [漢嶺勝利 00]
Here!
こっち
♪And all ♪
♪ 決して変わらない ♪
-Not bad! -Yeah!
- よし - いいぞ
Nice!
いいぞ
Great shot!
ナイス
Nice shot! Keep it up!
ナイス その調子
[Hongjing No. 8 High 6–0 Hanling Victory]
[宏景八高 06] [漢嶺勝利 00]
We beat Hanling Victory, you know that?
韓嶺に勝ったんだ 聞いてるか
[Little Savage Tribe]
[野人部落]
Qin was the MVP.
ＭＶＰは秦だった
Qin was unstoppable today.
今日の秦 すごかったんだ
Wen Chengye was incredible too!
文成業もめちゃくちゃイケてた
I really wish you could've seen how awesome we were.
先生にも俺たちの勇姿を 見て欲しかったな
[Little Savage Tribe]
[野人部落]
Ms. Lin, are you watching this?
林先生 見てるか
I can vouch for them.
私が証言する
They're not exaggerating at all.
みんな大げさには言ってない
[I can vouch for them. They're not exaggerating at all.]
[私が証言する みんな大げさに は言ってない]
When is
林先生
Ms. Lin coming back?
いつ戻ってくるんですか
[Superstar Slacker]
[干物見習い]
Wanxing,
星
no matter what happens,
何があっても
I'm here for you.
私がそばにいるから
[Superstar Slacker]
[干物見習い]
Those little rascals said
あいつらが言ってた
they're saving the victory banquet until you come back.
祝勝会は君が戻るまで 取っておくって
We really miss you.
みんな会いたがってる
Good night.
おやすみ